<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kerin Pithawala&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kerin Pithawala&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 18:16:54 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Overview of 3 Dimensional Array</title>
      <link>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/posts/thirdpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 18:16:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/posts/thirdpost/</guid>
      
        <description>A multidimensional array is an array consisting of more than 2 dimensions. We can perceive three dimensions at most. To visual 3-dimensional array, let&amp;rsquo;s take an example of a cube.
Therefore, the array is cube[3][3][3].
For better understanding, represent a 3-D array as a combination of 2-D arrays. Note: The two-dimensional array must have the same size.
img
To conclude, a three dimensional array has arr[sub-array number][row][column].
Application of 3-D array  To represent real-world location co-ordinates.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to 2-D Array</title>
      <link>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/posts/secondp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 20:13:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/posts/secondp/</guid>
      
        <description>Overview of two dimensional array A two-dimensional array is an array of array. For example, consider a sample time table.
Here, the days are an array. Each day consists of an array within them. Thus it forms a 2-D array with 6 columns and 7 rows. The text entered in each box acts as an element.
The advantages and disadvantages of a 2-dimensional array are the same as a 1-dimensional array as I mentioned in this blog on 1D Array.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/contact/</guid>
      
        <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 21:59:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/about/about/</guid>
      
        <description>My name is Kerin Pithawala. I am a final year undegraduate student at Narsee Monjee Institute of Management Studies. I am persuing Bachelor of Technology(Honors) in Computer Engineering with minors in IoT, Cloud Computing and Blockchain.
I am interested in software development and research.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction To 1-D Array</title>
      <link>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/posts/firstpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 21:17:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/posts/firstpost/</guid>
      
        <description>One Dimensional Array Simplified Array: A data structure which stores homogenous data types in continuous memory allocation is known as an Array. It stored several related items using a single name. Different elements can be accessed using the index.
Consider a cupboard in your local library. It has different sections for different genres of book. Each section can accommodate a specific number of books.
Now consider the section of Mathematics wherein one would only find books on mathematics.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>