<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kerin Pithawala&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kerin Pithawala&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 22:23:22 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Priority Queue</title>
      <link>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/posts/priorityqueue/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 22:23:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/posts/priorityqueue/</guid>
      
        <description>Consider a group of patients waiting outside the doctor&amp;rsquo;s cabin for consultation. The functioning of the clinic is First In First Out basis like a queue. Suddenly, a new patient arrives with a condition which requires immediate treatment.
 Then, the doctor would treat this patient first and then continue treating other patients like the previous order.
In a priority queue, each data element has priority. So that crucial data does not get stuck.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying for Mitacs Globalink Research Internship</title>
      <link>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/posts/mitacsgrifaq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 20:23:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/posts/mitacsgrifaq/</guid>
      
        <description>Introduction Mitacs Globalink Research Internship is a competitive initiative for international undergraduates from selected countries. Over 70 Universities in Canada host students every year from May to October. These universities offer research projects ranging from engineering, sciences to humanities. The applications usually start during August and the entire selection process can take upto 8 months.
My selection experience  The application form required applicants to do the following:
 Fill in the basic information: Name, email address, phone number, CGPA, University name etc.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Circular Queue</title>
      <link>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/posts/seventhpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 21:27:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/posts/seventhpost/</guid>
      
        <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s say another student wants to wait in the queue to get his/her assignment checked. There is space available on the bench, but the student cannot occupy it.
 If the students shift to left, then they can make space the new student. However, this is very time-consuming.
 So, logically the person would occupy the vacant seat.
 But, will make sure that when the professor calls the early entrants will go first.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Queue</title>
      <link>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/posts/sixthpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 09:32:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/posts/sixthpost/</guid>
      
        <description>A queue is a data structure which stores elements one after others.
A unique feature of this data structure is that we can use an array or linked list for its implementation. We are concerned about its functionality instead of it is implemented in code. Thus, the queue is an abstract data type.
Consider a group of students waiting outside the professor&amp;rsquo;s cabin in line for project submission.
 The queue increases when more people arrive.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Stack </title>
      <link>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/posts/fifthpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 21:54:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/posts/fifthpost/</guid>
      
        <description>A stack is a data structure which stores elements one above others. Consider a pile of coins. Each coin is a data element. Addition and removal of coins take place at one end. This place is called the top of the stack.
 Image credits: PixelBay
  A unique feature of this data structure is that we can use an array or linked list for its implementation. We are concerned about its functionality instead of it is implemented in code.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Linked List</title>
      <link>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/posts/fourthpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 20:13:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/posts/fourthpost/</guid>
      
        <description>Linked list as the name suggests is a list of elements grouped linearly.  Image credits: Wikimedia Commons
  A unit element in a linked list consists of the following components:
Data Address of neighbour element/s We refer to this unit element as a node. Therefore, a linked list is a set of nodes. The last node in the linked list points to null, indicating that the linked list has ended.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to 3 Dimensional Array</title>
      <link>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/posts/thirdpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 18:16:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/posts/thirdpost/</guid>
      
        <description>A multidimensional array is an array consisting of more than 2 dimensions. We can perceive three dimensions at most. To visual 3-dimensional array, let&amp;rsquo;s take an example of a cube.
 Cube
  Therefore, the array is cube[3][3][3].
For better understanding, represent a 3-D array as a combination of 2-D arrays. Note: The two-dimensional array must have the same size.
img
To conclude, a three dimensional array has arr[sub-array number][row][column].</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to 2-D Array</title>
      <link>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/posts/secondp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 20:13:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/posts/secondp/</guid>
      
        <description>Overview of two dimensional array A two-dimensional array is an array of array. For example, consider a sample time table.
 Time Table
  Here, the days are an array. Each day consists of an array within them. Thus it forms a 2-D array with 6 columns and 7 rows. The text entered in each box acts as an element.
The advantages and disadvantages of a 2-dimensional array are the same as a 1-dimensional array as I mentioned in this blog on 1D Array.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/contact/</guid>
      
        <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 21:59:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/about/about/</guid>
      
        <description>My name is Kerin Pithawala. I am a final year undegraduate student at Narsee Monjee Institute of Management Studies. I am persuing Bachelor of Technology(Honors) in Computer Engineering with minors in IoT, Cloud Computing and Blockchain.
I am interested in software development and research.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to 1-D Array</title>
      <link>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/posts/firstpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 21:17:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerinpithawala.github.io/Blog/posts/firstpost/</guid>
      
        <description>One Dimensional Array Simplified Array: A data structure which stores homogenous data types in continuous memory allocation is known as an Array. It stored several related items using a single name. Different elements can be accessed using the index.
Consider a cupboard in your local library. It has different sections for different genres of book. Each section can accommodate a specific number of books.  Analogy Illustration
  Now consider the section of Mathematics wherein one would only find books on mathematics.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>